Albany Fonblanque Collection, 1784-1875: Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections.
Albany Fonblanque Collection
1784-1875
C0157
Princeton University. Library. Dept. of Rare Books and Special Collections Manuscripts Division One Washington Road Princeton, New Jersey 08544 USA
0.2 linear feet 1 half-size archival box
Fonblanque, Albany, 1793-1872.
Consists primarily of letters sent to Albany Fonblanque as editor of the Examiner (London).
Albany Fonblanque was a nineteenth-century English editor and journalist.
The collection consists primarily of letters sent to Fonblanque as editor of the Examiner (London). Among the correspondents are Marguerite Blessington, William Lisle Bowles, Edward Bulwer-Lytton, Rosina Lytton, the comte d'Orsay, George Grote, Sir George Cornewall Lewis, and Lord John Russell. Also included are two letters by Fonblanque to Lord Lytton, one unidentified manuscript, and one autograph manuscript by Charles Reynell regarding Leigh Hunt's censorship trial.
Folders are in alphabetical order by last name.
The collection is open for research.
AM 13115
Hunt, Leigh, 1784-1859 -- Trials, litigation, etc.; Orsay, Alfred Guillaume Gabriel, comte d', 1801-1852.; Censorship -- England -- 19th century.; Correspondence -- 19th century.; Editors -- England -- London -- 19th century.; British literature
- Blessington, Marguerite: 3 Letters to Albany Fonblanque, 1849; 1 folder (Folder 1)
- Canon Bowles: Letter to Editor of the Examiner, 17 January 1837; 1 folder (Folder 2)
- Brougham, Henry Peter: 2 Letters to Albany Fonblanque, undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
- Bulwer-Lytton, Edward George, 1839-1869; 1 folder (Folder 4)
- Bulwer, Henry Lytton, 1835-1842; 1 folder (Folder 5)
- Bulwer, Rosina Doyle, undated; 1 folder (Folder 6)
- Campbell, George: Letter to Albany Fonblanque, 24 February 1843; 1 folder (Folder 7)
- Clarendon, Lord: Letter to Albany Fonblanque, 30 March 1852; 1 folder (Folder 8)
- D'Orsay, Alfred Count of: 11 Letters to Albany Fonblanque, 1831-1847; 1 folder (Folder 9)
- Dunraven, Windham, undated; 1 folder (Folder 10)
- Fellowes, Robert, 1830-1835; 1 folder (Folder 11)
- Fox, C. R: Letters to Albany Fonblanque, 1838-1848; 1 folder (Folder 12)
- Goff, Richard: Letter to Albany Fonblanque, 1832; 1 folder (Folder 13)
- Granville, George Leveson Gower: Letter to Albany Fonblanque, 30 January 1858; 1 folder (Folder 14)
- Grey, Lord: Letter to Albany Fonblanque, 8 December 1834; 1 folder (Folder 15)
- Grote, George, undated; 1 folder (Folder 16)
- Hobhouse, John Cam, 1855-1857; 1 folder (Folder 17)
- Hook, Theodore: Letter to John Fonblanque, undated; 1 folder (Folder 18)
- Hunt, H: Letter to Albany Fonblanque, 31 January 1854; 1 folder (Folder 19)
- Hunt, James Henry Leigh, undated; 1 folder (Folder 20)
- Lambton, John George, 1834-1835; 1 folder (Folder 21)
- Lennox, Henry Gordon: Letter to John Fonblanque, 12 April 1784; 1 folder (Folder 22)
- Lewis, George, undated; 1 folder (Folder 23)
- Llandaff, Bishop of: Letter to Albany Fonblanque, 23 December 1839; 1 folder (Folder 24)
- Minto, William, 24 February 1875; 1 folder (Folder 25)
- Morgan, Sydney, undated; 1 folder (Folder 26)
- Mulgrave, Lord: Letters to Albany Fonblanque, undated; 1 folder (Folder 27)
- Murray, Charles: Letter to Lord Normanby, 10 June 1842; 1 folder (Folder 28)
- Normanby, Constanten Henry, undated; 1 folder (Folder 29)
- Nugent, George, undated; 1 folder (Folder 30)
- Reynell, Charles, undated; 1 folder (Folder 31)
- Russell, Lord John: 4 Letters to Geo. Poulett Scrope, 1843-1853; 1 folder (Folder 32)
- Savage, Marmion: Letter to Albany Fonblanque, undated; 1 folder (Folder 33)
- Savage, Marmion, undated; 1 folder (Folder 34)
- Trevelyan, Sir Charles Edward, undated; 1 folder (Folder 35)
- Villiers, Charles, undated; 1 folder (Folder 36)
- Ward, Sir Henry, undated; 1 folder (Folder 37)
- Wood, C., 22 April 1841; 1 folder (Folder 38)
- Unidentified Letters, undated; 1 folder (Folder 39)
- 32101037584768 (Box 1)